The neurodiverse population remains
a largely untapped pool of talent.
Unemployment runs as high as 80%.
Even when they're working, highly capable,
neurodiverse people are often
underemployed.
Many times, despite
having required skill sets and
solid credentials, they
have to settle for menial jobs.
These poor numbers are
due to the way companies
screen and hire their
possible candidates.
Fostering an inclusive workplace begins
with making neurodiversity a priority.
Employers and recruiters need to revamp
their hiring practices so as not to miss
out on any of the neurodiverse talent
that could help the company flourish.
Recruitment of people on the
spectrum is only the first step.
Employers need to make certain
accommodations for a fulfilling work
environment for people
across the spectrum.
Encouraging neurodiversity makes
organizations inclusive and innovative.
Employees who identify on
the neurodiverse spectrum
bring with them new
ways of looking at things.
This encourages the entire
team to think creatively.
Merging unique perspectives and ideas
within a team naturally fosters an
environment that is innovative
and forward-thinking.